fired up. Eighth pick, uh, Jordan Tyson,
Arizona State. Um, this is a really,
really fun process for us just to kind
of go through this entire journey.
Obviously, it's the first pick. We got
plenty more to go, but, uh, you know,
Jordan's a really exciting player for
us. A guy who can play a ton of
positions, his versatility, uh, the way
he attacks the football when he catches
the football, the way he can separate
with at the line of scrimmage, at the
catch point. A lot of positives with
this one. And so, uh, we're fired up.
Obviously, a lot of the conversation
around him over the course of the
pre-draft process centered around his
injuries, health, things like that. What
was it that you learned throughout the
process that made you all feel
comfortable with where he was?
>> Yeah. Um, I think, you know, obviously
guys are going to go through things
where they have to navigate and, you
know, for credit to him, you know, he
had to navigate a knee, clavicle, uh,
you know, the hamstring stuff that he
had this year. Um, and he battled
through it. And I think that's credit to
him is his willingness to battle. I
mean, you know, he hurts his hamstring
in this, you know, Texas Tech game and
he makes the plays to basically win the
game at the end of the game and so uh
this guy's a really tough football
player. Uh he's battled some things and
I think all that's uh positive and, you
know, he worked out uh through this
whole process, kind of recovered and
he's in a great place.
>> How much, if anything, did that workout
contribute to you guys feeling okay
about the injury history?
>> Uh again, I think it view it just as
like a checking base point. Uh, you
know, those are always nice little
confirmations when you see the guy move
around and and run some routes. Uh,
obviously it wasn't going to be a lot.
You know, it's just a quick workout in
April, but hey, all those things count
and all those things add to again, uh,
you talk about, hey, there's always
questions with every player and you're
trying to eliminate as many questions as
he can. And hey, if a guy works out in
April and shows that he's running around
and making plays like that, then uh,
obviously you have a few less questions.
>> At what point did you stop having like
when were those questions eliminated for
you guys? pretty much after medical
test.
>> Yeah. Yeah. For for a while. Yeah. We
felt comfortable with him. We felt like
he's uh you go through the whole medical
process, you go through the whole
evaluation, this guy uh you know, he was
ready to go.
>> Ken, he was coached by Hinesford in
college. What did you like about his
blocking skills?
>> Yeah, I think uh you know, you have
evidence on film. Uh you have evidence
on film of him uh you know, really going
in there and blocking. And you know,
obviously for all these guys coming from
college football, a lot of times there's
going to be a little bit more of a, uh,
ask to go do it even more consistently.
And so, uh, you I think to see his
progress when he was with Hines at
Arizona State the last couple years, you
see the steps he made in a number of
areas. You know, hey, he's coming in the
NFL. He's got plenty of stuff that he's
going to continue to build and get
better at. And, uh, we got the right
kind of guy to do it.
>> How do you feel he compliments Chris's
skill set?
>> Yeah.
I think the the big thing with all of
our receivers and really you can look at
probably almost that whole group
collectively is their versatility, their
ability to line up in multiple
positions, line up in a lot of spots.
You watch Jordan's career. Um he's lined
up in a number of places. And so
certainly, you know, him and Chris and
they and all the other guys, their
versatility is a positive for us. We're
not going to be stuck in guys playing
one position. U you know, certainly
we'll have home bases for all those
guys, but they'll be able to line up
wherever they need to. Does he provide
something that you guys didn't have
previously unique about now?
>> Um, that's a good question. I think uh,
you know, I think he compliments those
other guys. I think uh, his ability
again to line up in multiple spots. I
think does a great job at the line of
scrimmage. He does a great job at the
break point. You know, things that he'll
still need to improve on, but um, you
know, his ability to make plays
downfield. You know, obviously he's
everyone's got the social media clips
that I'm sure everyone's seen of him
making plays downfield. And, um, I think
credit to him. The thing that I was
really excited when we had a chance to
evaluate him and kind of watch games
was, you know, their biggest games, he
came up in those big time moments. I
think that's credit to him that, you
know, when they go play these, you know,
the Texas Tech game, you know, comes to
mind, the TCU game comes to mind. Like
when he has these opportunities to go
play against, you know, the best in
their division or conference, I should
say, he played really well.
>> He he said growing up like being
something that was shorter for a long
time like made him a better route
runner, a little more detailed and all
that. Do you see that kind of in how he
plays?
>> Yeah, I think that's a really good
assessment. U he plays, you know, he has
ability to play inside and play in the
slot and play with some wiggle. Uh you
see the basketball background, you see
the track background to him. Uh you
know, I think his ability, he's a
multiport kid and so he's got so much
more versatility in his game.
>> What stood out to you about him
character-wise? I mean, you mentioned
like the going through adversity stuff,
but just in terms of your meetings and
conversations with him.
>> Yeah, fun kid, great kid. worked his
tail off the last couple years and uh
you know I think you know his brother's
in in the NBA and it's really a unique
experience really cool experience for
their family but what's really cool is
this guy you felt the football junkie in
him u this guy really knows football he
really knows the receivers in the league
and you know you're asking about which
receivers are you watching that you're
trying to learn from I'm learning from
this guy and here's why and that this
guy here's why and I mean he he's got a
really u smart head to him you know as
far as a football acumen and awareness
to what's going on around our league and
everything. And so, uh, you know, it was
really impressive.
>> Was there something you wanted to
prioritize going into or is it just kind
of how it shook out? Like, how did you
feel about kind of going into what you
guys wanted to accomplish?
>> Yeah, it wasn't a must do on in the
first round. Um, obviously you
understand, hey, these first rounds take
a lot of different paths and uh, we were
prepared to handle a lot of different
uh, routines or potential scenarios here
and um, this one turned out great. You
know, we're fired up to get Jordan and
so uh, we got plenty of work to do. We
got plenty more picks to u, you know, go
through as we go through this whole
process next two days and so it'll be a
lot of fun. kind of that's been like
thrown about is
>> the organization wanted to to make sure
Tyler has all the tools at his disposal
to be successful. Was that is that
something that y'all were thinking about
in this process like surrounding the
quarterback with the talent?
>> I think that's an important aspect.
Obviously, we we feel good with where
Tyler's progressing and um anytime you
can add pieces um for him as he
continues to grow and especially, you
know, a lot of these guys are younger
guys that are, you know, kind of work
together for a number of years certainly
we anticipate and so um this is a great
ad to that group and so uh we got a lot
of other work other things that we want
to accomplish through the next two days,
but uh I thought it was a good step. in
that cloud that you usually get to as
your pick is approaching. I mean, was
was he at was it like a receiver and
then multiple other positions or or I
mean was
>> Yeah, we had other positions in that in
that discussion point there. And so, um
yeah, few different scenarios we can go
through, but again, I think the Jeff and
Mickey and the whole scouting department
and executive group, I mean, we go
through all these scenarios. I mean,
it's really a watch it go and we've
already talked through the scenario.
There's not really a negotiation or a
discussion about it. uh we've gone
through these scenarios. If this is what
it looks like, this is what we're
dealing and we felt really good about
Jordan.
>> A lot of buzz early in the day that you
guys could possibly trade up in the
first. How accurate was that? And did
you guys get close at all and moving up?
>> Mickey's always calling people checking
in on things, navigating this thing.
He's, you know, the best at doing that.
And so, uh, you know, I think he just
does a really good job keeping an eye on
the league and understanding what
opportunities present theirel. May maybe
it wasn't specifically by design first
few hours of free agency to go guard and
running back and then
>> uh add the tight end now add the
receiver in the first round of the draft
but adding all those pieces in in your
first full off season. I mean how much
do you think that's going to help you
implement your vision for this off?
>> Yeah, those are all you know I think the
big thing is they're all awesome people.
They're really good football players.
They'll be great in the locker room. Um,
you know, we want this group to come
together and and and work together and
and that that includes, you know, all
three phases of this team. And so, uh,
again, there's plenty of acquisitions we
got to keep working through here the
next couple days and we'll continue to
do that.
>> When he when he came here on his 30
visit, was it the football junkie part
that stood out the most or was it
something else maybe from that that
visit that really stood out to you?
>> Yeah, my exposure again when you go
through these 30 visits, they they
experience just about our entire
building. you know, they go through uh
they meet with everyone. My exposure was
really getting to know uh Jordan as a
person a little bit more because the
combine's a really fast conversation.
It's 20 minutes and you're out. You
know, it's first impression and that's
about it. So, uh getting to spend some
time getting to know him a little bit
more as a person, hearing his story, but
I thought the the football junkie part
was cool to me, just getting to know,
you know, where his mind was. And so, um
you know, his brother's in the NBA and
that's that's awesome. It's a really
cool experience. uh he loves football,
you know, he loves football and so uh
you know, credit to him.
>> What not to harp on the injury thing,
but just from a process standpoint, how
involved is like Ted Wrath, for
instance, in terms of building out a
plan for this potential draft selection
as you're leading to this point?
>> Yeah, it's it's a collaborative effort.
Obviously, we go through the medical
evaluation phase of this, uh have those
conversations. Obviously, Mickey and
Jeff have to kind of navigate that.
They've done that for a long time and so
they have to feel comfortable with where
that's at and then uh you know once we
acquire these guys it's about building
plans for these guys to be successful
and certainly to be successful you got
to be on the field and so uh you know
Jordan Jordan will be ready to go. Was
the was there any information you
received that made you feel comfortable
with that like that he could be
healthier at the next level like with
Tyler for instance last year was just
broken like he just had broken bones so
it wasn't like ligament stuff but he
yeah play like ligament stuff like what
made you guys kind of comfortable that
it's not going to happen maybe as
frequently as
>> Yeah obviously this was you know he he
had a hamstring issue last year and it
comes up and there's probably no player
that's immune to that. uh those things
happen, you know, and that he kind of
tried to fight through it and it it just
kind of uh lingered a little bit and
those things happen and you know, a
couple of the other injuries. I mean,
Tyler was experienced there's some
things that, you know, they're
unfortunate things that happen in
playing football and there's risk
associated with football uh always when
you play and you know, a knee or a
clavicle or some of those things and
Tyler navigated that in his college
career as well. with uh Jordan, the we
see the the twitchiness, the the
explosive plays, all those things, but
is there anything maybe a little bit
unheralded about him that maybe stood
out to you all that's, you know, kind of
stood out? In addition,
>> I thought uh yeah, I again I think the
release pattern, you saw that his
releases, his ability to attack the
football, you know, he's he's very
focused on the football at the catch
point. He attacks the football. Um I
enjoy all the little things. I enjoy
that he's always looking to find someone
to go block. uh you know when it's a run
play and the ball's going over here and
he's he's turning to go find someone um
you know you can see him celebrating his
teammates when they score you know all
those little things to me those are all
just confirmation that you're getting
the right kind of guy and so uh yeah
we're fired up a candidate to be a
return specialist as well
>> uh we haven't gone that road lately but
uh we'll see we'll see how it goes
obviously he's got experience in it and
so uh we certainly have a number of guys
have done that before
>> for uh for those of us that have to do
live shots tomorrow to ask in a head
question here. Uh how excited are you
about tomorrow and like when you look at
the board, do you feel like there's an
abundance of talent for you all still in
rounds two and three?
>> This is the fun part. Yeah. The the
first day you get one pick. Uh it's it's
very exciting, but then uh we get sit
there and watch all these things happen.
And so uh you know, we're continue to
build. We got a number of acquisitions
to make over the next couple days. And
uh this is about building a team and
this will be a lot of fun.
So Colin, when when you get a player
like Jordan, he goes from a three star
athlete in high school to the eighth
pick overall. What does that say to
yourself?
>> Yeah, he's just an awesome kid. Um his
journey, what he's done through his high
school career, playing at three
different high schools, navigating a
bunch of stuff there, going to Colorado,
uh you know, for whatever reason just
doesn't quite, you know, work out the
way way you certainly hope it does. And
he goes to Arizona State again. I think
just uh you know these guys who've you
know navigate stuff, been resilient,
have a ton of toughness, they love
football. You get a bunch of those type
of guys, we'll be just fine.
>> You mentioned something that Jeff had
said at the combine to try and get under
his skin or you know what he was talking
about or elaborate.
>> I don't know specifics. You can ask
Jordan probably next time. But uh Jeff
always likes to poke at guys a little
bit, have a little bit of fun, ask him,
you know, maybe about a little bit of uh
question about, you know, his experience
in college football and kind of, you
know, see how they respond. Jordan
Jordan was great.
>> He did mention that he was able to sit
down with Chris when he took his visit.
Is is that typical that you would have a
potential draft meet with a star at the
position?
>> Not necessarily. Uh kind of happened,
you know, he was walking through the
building and saw saw Chris. And so, uh,
you know, again, those players, a lot of
these players have relationships outside
of, you know, even before they become
teammates. And so, uh, I don't know all
the details there, but I know they were,
you know, Chris happened to be in the
facility that day and, uh, crossed paths
with them and I know he said he saw him
and, um, yeah, that's that's a good good
group right there.
>> Nick, you mentioned you obviously
elicit the advice of someone like Tyler
Shutton, someone like Chris Bell, who
was his teammate in college. But when it
came to receivers you were evaluating in
this draft, did you pick the brain of of
Tyler on on guys like like Jordan? Um,
you know, certainly with Chris's
experience, you know, that's a guy that
he's played with and so certainly you're
gonna want to get to know his experience
with him. Uh, you know, I think Tyler
felt good with our our process. He
understood that, you know, we'll we'll
figure this out at some point, you know,
over the next few days or next through
the offseason as far as trying to
acquire more more guys. And so, uh,
that's all part of this process. And so,
Tyler's Tyler's been great.
>> Kind of touched on it earlier, but like
how much better do you think you guys
got offense this off season? Yeah, I
hope again I think we brought in some
really high character players. They're
really talented players. Um I feel like
this group there's a ton of work to do.
There's a ton of work through an
offseason process. You know, you can
acquire talent all you want. Uh it's all
got to come together and everyone's got
to be on the same page and and um you
know, so that's the work that we get to
do moving forward and so um you know, we
just got to keep going.
>> Do you uh prototype NBA ties or is that
the guy?
>> That's right. You do like the NBA. Yeah.
Um hey, it doesn't doesn't hurt. Doesn't
hurt. Uh you can see some crossover
moves with his release pattern. So you
can certainly see him playing basketball
probably, you know, shooting hoops with
his brother growing up. Uh you can see
some of that.
>> You mentioned that Jeff likes to do that
with prospects, right? As far as like
maybe poking a little bit. How much does
maybe that reveal the way that they're
able to take that and maybe the way that
they even respond to to some of that?
>> Yeah. Hey, any chance we get to spend
time with these guys, it's awesome. You
get to know these guys as people.
Obviously, we watch plenty of film, but
hey, we draft these guys, we're bringing
them in, we spend a lot of time
together, and so we we want awesome guys
that we love being around uh here. And
so, uh you know, Jeff does a great job
with this process. He's really thorough.
He's really detailed. He knows these
guys inside and out through the whole
their whole college journey. And so, you
know, especially with these guys
transferring and just being around a lot
of different coaches, there's just so
much more movement in college football
nowadays that sometimes it's fun to just
kind of connect the dots of, okay, how
did this process go for you and, you
know, this journey and how you got to
this point? And so, we like to dig on
dig on all that sort of stuff with these
guys. was his like you mentioned him
like rising to big moments in games and
stuff, but like was that kind of and I I
know there are plenty of players that do
that, but like was that an outlier in
that regard to you involved like the
receivers you scouted during this
process or like did it was it something
that separated himself through the
process?
>> Well, I I think certainly most of these
guys I mean the guys that I would
probably imagine the guys all that went
today I mean they they had their
moments. They had their moments in big
time games. Um, you know, but but again,
as we went through Jordan's thing, I I
thought those were big time
opportunities to showcase him against
the best guys that he went against. and
uh he's done it for a couple years now
at Arizona